export const FINANCIALACCOUNTINGA2020 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. A debit entry in affixed asset account represents _______",
A: "An increase in the fixed asset account",
B: "A decrease in the fixed asset account",
C: "A profit on disposal of the fixed asset",
D: "A loss on disposal of the fixed asset",
answer: "A. An increase in the fixed asset account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. When bank charges are discovered in a bank statement, the adjustment is effected in the __________",
A: "Bank reconciliation statement",
B: "Cash book",
C: "Suspense account",
D: "Bank loan account",
answer: "B. Cash book",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. The double entry for interest on drawings by a partner is debit __________",
A: "Partner’s current account; credit Appropriation Account",
B: "Profit and Loss account: Credit Interest Account",
C: "Appropriation Account; Credit Partner’s Current Account",
D: "Interest Account; credit Profit and Loss Account",
answer: "A. Partner’s current account; credit Appropriation Account",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. A credit purchase of GH¢200 from Osae was posted to the account of Osei. This is an error of ________",
A: "Principle",
B: "Commission",
C: "Omission",
D: "Original entry",
answer: "B. Commission",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The net figure for debtors in the balance sheet is _________",
A: "Le47,025",
B: "Le46,550",
C: "Le46,600",
D: "Le45,500",
answer: "A. Le47,025",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. The provision for doubtful debts to be charged to Profit and Loss Account is ________",
A: "Le2,500",
B: "Le1,475",
C: "Le2,450",
D: "Le1,000",
answer: "B. Le1,475",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A piece of office equipment bought for use was found to be defective and returned to the supplier. The subsidiary book to record this transaction is ________",
A: "Returns outwards journal",
B: "Returns inwards journal",
C: "Purchases journal",
D: "General journal",
answer: "A. Returns outwards journal",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. In a situation of incomplete records, profit is determined as ______",
A: "Closing Capital – Drawings + Opening Capital",
B: "Closing Capital – Drawings – Opening Capital",
C: "Closing Capital + Drawings – Opening Capital",
D: "Closing Capital + Drawings + Opening Capital",
answer: "C. Closing Capital + Drawings – Opening Capital",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The document which serves as the authority to incur expenditure in the public sector is _________",
A: "Warrant",
B: "Vote",
C: "Budget",
D: "Voucher",
answer: "A. Warrant",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. A debit balance of GH¢420 on the purchases ledger control account means that the _________",
A: "Trade creditors were overpaid by GH¢420",
B: "Trade creditors are owed GH¢420",
C: "Goods returned to trade creditors amount to GH¢420",
D: "Total supplies from trade creditors amounted to GH¢420",
answer: "A. Trade creditors were overpaid by GH¢420",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. A total of D9,160 was entered in the sales account as D9,610. To correct this error: debit",
A: "Sales Account D450; Credit Sales Day Book D450",
B: "Sales Day Book D450; Credit Sales Account D450",
C: "Sales Account D450; Credit Suspense Account D450",
D: "Suspense Account D450; credit Sales Account D450",
answer: "C. Sales Account D450; Credit Suspense Account D450",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The profit available for sharing by the partners is ___________",
A: "N90,000",
B: "N40,500",
C: "N36,000",
D: "N27,500",
answer: "C. N36,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The balance in Chikum’s Current Account is",
A: "N14,000",
B: "N9,000",
C: "N8,000",
D: "N4,000",
answer: "B. N9,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Bubu’s share of profit is",
A: "N16,000",
B: "N12,000",
C: "N8,000",
D: "N4,000",
answer: "B. N12,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Recognition of profit when goods are sold and the buyer takes ownership of them is in line with _________",
A: "Realization concept",
B: "Matching concept",
C: "Business entity concept",
D: "Going concern concept",
answer: "A. Realization concept",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. The purpose of preparing a trading account is to ascertain _______",
A: "Average cost",
B: "Gross profit",
C: "Cost of goods sold",
D: "Cost of goods available for sale",
answer: "B. Gross profit",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. A trader adds 25% on cost as profit. The profit on sales of $300,000 would be _________",
A: "$75,000",
B: "$60,000",
C: "$50,000",
D: "$25,000",
answer: "A. $75,000",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The accounting concept which distinguishes an enterprise from its owners is _________",
A: "Money measurement concept",
B: "Dual aspect concept",
C: "Going concern concept",
D: "Business entity concept",
answer: "D. Business entity concept",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Eze introduced his private car into his business. The aspect of accounting equation of the business that would be affected are _____",
A: "Asset and Capital",
B: "Capital and Profit",
C: "Liabilities and Assets",
D: "Capital and Liabilities",
answer: "A. Asset and Capital",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Debtors and credit sales for a period are D120.00 and D600.00 respectively. The debtor’s payment period would be _________",
A: "1825 days",
B: "365 days",
C: "73 days",
D: "5 days",
answer: "C. 73 days",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Subscriptions credited to Income and Expenditure Account for 2018 was ______",
A: "N9,990,000",
B: "N9,690,000",
C: "N9,630,000",
D: "N9,330,00",
answer: "C. N9,630,000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Total expenses debited to Income and Expenditure Account for 2018 was _______",
A: "N12,610,000",
B: "N8,095,000",
C: "N4,515,000",
D: "N4,095,000",
answer: "D. N4,095,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The surplus for the year 2018 was ________",
A: "N7,865,000",
B: "N7,535,000",
C: "N5,845,000",
D: "N5,235,000",
answer: "B. N7,535,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. A non-cash expense chargeable against profit and loss account is ________",
A: "Insurance payable",
B: "Debenture interest",
C: "Provision for doubtful debts",
D: "Rent and rates",
answer: "C. Provision for doubtful debts",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The cost incurred on goods purchased for production which can be traced to a particular unit is classified as _________",
A: "Direct labour",
B: "Direct expenses",
C: "Direct materials",
D: "Factory overhead",
answer: "B. Direct expenses",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. The value of closing stock of finished goods in the trading account is ________",
A: "D37,800",
B: "D20,000",
C: "D19,800",
D: "D18,000",
answer: "C. D19,800",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. The value of closing stock of finished goods that would be shown in the balance sheet is ________",
A: "D37,800",
B: "D20,000",
C: "D19,800",
D: "18,000",
answer: "C. D19,800",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Items shown in the manufacturing account include: \nI. Purchase of raw materials \nII. Purchases of finished goods \nIII. Carriage inwards \nIV. Carriage outwards",
A: "I and II only",
B: "I and III only",
C: "I, II and III only",
D: "I, III and IV only",
answer: "C. I, II and III only",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The cash paid by Kwamenah was _______",
A: "Le 43,650",
B: "Le 43,500",
C: "Le 37,800",
D: "Le 36,666",
answer: "D. Le 36,666",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Kwamenah would record the 10% discount in the _________",
A: "Sales journal",
B: "Cash book",
C: "Purchases journal",
D: "Journal proper",
answer: "C. Purchases journal",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Doe and Sons Limited would enter the 3% discount in the ______",
A: "Sales Journal",
B: "Cash book",
C: "Purchases Journal",
D: "Journal proper",
answer: "B. Cash book",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. A partner who contributes capital but does not participate in the day-to-day running of the business is __________",
A: "An active partner",
B: "A limited partner",
C: "A nominal partner",
D: "A sleeping partner",
answer: "D. A sleeping partner",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. An example of real account is __________",
A: "Computer Repairs Account",
B: "Computer Insurance Account",
C: "Office Computer Account",
D: "Depreciation of Computer Account",
answer: "C. Office Computer Account",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. The concept that guides a firm to adopt a regular method of recording transactions in its books over a period is ____________",
A: "Periodicity concept",
B: "Consistency concept",
C: "Going concern concept",
D: "Historical cost concept",
answer: "B. Consistency concept",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. A business extracted its trial balance and discovered that the total of the credit side exceeded the total of the debit side. Pending further investigation, the difference would be _________",
A: "Credited to Suspense Account",
B: "Debited to Suspense Account",
C: "Credited to Profit and Loss Account",
D: "Debited to profit and Loss Account",
answer: "B. Debited to Suspense Account",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The Salaries that would be charged to Profit and Loss Account for the year 2017 is ___________",
A: "GH¢ 197,000",
B: "GH¢ 157,000",
C: "GH¢ 142,000",
D: "GH¢ 127,000",
answer: "B. GH¢ 157,000",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. The Electricity that would be charged to Profit and Loss Account for the year 2017 is _________",
A: "GH¢ 197,000",
B: "GH¢ 157,000",
C: "GH¢ 238,000",
D: "GH¢ 236,000",
answer: "D. GH¢ 236,000",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. The Stationery that would be shown in the Balance Sheet as at 31st December 2017 is _________",
A: "GH¢ 139,000",
B: "GH¢ 113,000",
C: "GH¢ 36,000",
D: "GH¢ 13,000",
answer: "C. GH¢ 36,0000",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Accounting equation of a business shows the __________",
A: "Current assets and current liabilities only",
B: "Difference between current assets and liabilities",
C: "Assets and the sources of financing them",
D: "Owner’s interest in the business only",
answer: "C. Assets and the sources of financing them",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. The internal users of accounting information are the _________",
A: "Creditors",
B: "Employees",
C: "Investors",
D: "Customers",
answer: "B. Employees",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. A computer set bought for N150,000 was disposed for N45,000 after some years of use. The profit on disposal was N7,500. Accumulated depreciation at the time of disposal was ________",
A: "N112,500",
B: "N105,000",
C: "N97,5000",
D: "N37,500",
answer: "A. N112,500",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. Accumulated fund of a club is equivalent to its _________",
A: "Net worth",
B: "Gross worth",
C: "Total assets",
D: "Total liabilities",
answer: "A. Net worth",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The cost of sales for sportswear Department was _________",
A: "GH¢ 127,400",
B: "GH¢120,900",
C: "GH¢ 83,800",
D: "GH¢ 76,200",
answer: "C. GH¢ 83,800",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. The cost of sales for Cosmetics Department was _________",
A: "GH¢127,400",
B: "GH¢120,900",
C: "GH¢83,800",
D: "GH¢76,200",
answer: "A. GH¢127,400",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. The gross profit for Sportswear Department was ________",
A: "GH¢76,200",
B: "GH¢73,800",
C: "GH¢66,200",
D: "GH¢58,60",
answer: "C. GH¢66,200",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Income received in advance is treated in the balance sheet as a _________",
A: "Current liability",
B: "Current asset",
C: "Long term liability",
D: "Fixed asset",
answer: "A. Current liability",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Discount allowed N2,000; Bad debts N1,000 Cheque received from customers N24,000 Returns inwards N500 Sales ledger balance at the beginning N2,000 The amount of sales is _________",
A: "N29,500",
B: "N26,000",
C: "N25,500",
D: "N24,000",
answer: "C. N25,500",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The document which contains the internal regulations of a limited liability company is the __________",
A: "Certificate of Incorporation",
B: "Prospectus",
C: "Article of Association",
D: "Memorandum of Association",
answer: "C. Article of Association",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The excess of net assets acquired over purchase consideration is ___________",
A: "Capital reserve",
B: "Goodwill",
C: "Purchase price",
D: "Discount",
answer: "A. Capital reserve",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. A method of charging depreciation at a fixed percentage of the net book value is ___________",
A: "Straight line method",
B: "Reducing balance method",
C: "Sum of the years’ digits method",
D: "Revaluation method",
answer: "B. Reducing balance method",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},


]